FUKUNAGA COMMERCIAL STREET
(福永商店街)
Phew.
嘿咻
I'm beat.
累死我了
Darling, come!
老公 你快来啊
What's the matter? Why are you yelling?
真是的 怎么啦 叫这么大声
Just come with me now.
快点来就对了
Geez. What could be possibly...
真是的 到底怎么了…
Kita?
小北
UMA MUSUME PRETTY DERBY SEASON 3
《赛马娘 Pretty Derby 第三季》
"EPISODE 12: KITASAN BLACK" Thank you for coming
(第12话 北部玄驹) 感谢各位前来参加这场记者会
I asked Mr. Trainer to gather you here
今天之所以会拜托训练师请各位来
because I have a big announcement to make.
是因为想向各位宣布我的一项决定
I, Kitasan Black,
本人 北部玄驹
will retire from Twinkle Series
将在完成今年所有活动后
after completing this year's races.
从闪光系列赛中引退
I have always been able to complete all my races safely so far.
一直以来 我都平平安安地 跑完了每一场的比赛
And after each training or race, I wouldn't feel tired.
不管做再多的练习 或是比赛结束后 我都不觉得会累
But after the previous Tenno Sho, I can visibly feel
但是 在上次的秋季天皇赏中 我明显感觉到了
that my body is not what it used to be.
我的身体已经要过了巅峰期
I believe this is the final year
所以我认为 只有今年剩下的这些赛事
that I can deliver my best performance.
可以让我做出最好的表现
And that's why I made the decision to retire.
所以才会做出这样的决定
Which race will you participate in next?
那么接下来您会参加哪些比赛呢
Japan Cup.
我会直接参加日本杯的比赛
And
然后…
Arima Kinen will be my last race.
有马纪念将会是我的引退赛
I will do my best
我将会拿出我所有实力
and race without regrets.
跑出一场无怨无悔的好比赛
I count on your continuous support.
还请各位支持我到最后
Why?
为什么
She just won Tenno Sho.
她不是赢下了秋季天皇赏吗
We know when our body is failing us.
那是只有自己才能明白的异样感
Kita must have felt that way.
而小北感觉到了对吧
So she found the best time to retire and announced it.
找出最适合引退的时机点 然后公布
Huh?
咦
Yet,
但是…
she continues to chase after the title of all titles,
即便如此 她还是往前追求 那个比最强还要更高的荣誉
the autumn triple crown.
也就是想要夺下 秋季资深三冠的那个姿态
Is she doing this on purpose or not? We don't know.
这到底是她有意为之 又或者是无意间的举动
She knows how to present herself and commands attention.
她很清楚要如何 表现自己还有吸引众人
It seems like
看来她最后的这些比赛
"ROYCE AND ROYCE" she is approaching
(Royce and Royce)
her final match with an attitude
有必要不只是用尊敬的心
that's more than veneration.
而是用更加崇高的态度去看待
I see.
原来如此…
Thank you, everyone.
今天真的很谢谢大家
Don't mention it. It's nothing at all.
别在意 小事一椿
-Kitasan... -Quit crying, Special.
-北部… -不可以哭哦 小周
Diamond, thank you for being here too.
光钻 也谢谢你能来
Mhm.
不会
Don't mention it.
别在意
You will begin training for Japan Cup tomorrow.
明天将会再度开始进行 针对日本杯的训练
Yes, sir.
是
Please put me through a stricter training.
还请对我进行 比以往更为严格的训练
Well...
这…
I have decided
我决定了
to do my best in my last matches.
我要在剩下的比赛里 展现出我的一切
So, please...
所以…
All right.
我明白了
Thank you so much!
还请您多多鞭策我
Cheval.
骏逸
Did you watch Kitasan's press conference?
你看了北部的记者会了吗
Yes.
嗯
I joined halfway through.
从中间开始看的
I see.
这样啊
It must be lonely.
一定会很空虚吧
She has always been with us.
毕竟她一直都跟我们在一起
Huh?
咦
Lonely...
空虚…
HISHI AKEBONO
(菱曙)
Groove.
槽姐
You're calling me that again...
喂 那个叫法…
Whatever.
算了
Please focus on your training.
还有 在训练时不要分心
Or you'll hurt yourself.
可能会发生意外的
Is Kitasan's press conference bothering you?
你很在意北部的那场记者会吗
Yes.
是的
I can't recover fast enough.
我没办法赶上
I promised to race with her.
明明跟她约好 有朝一日要一起比赛
I want to race with her, compete against her.
我很想再跟她一起上场比赛 一起竞争
This is a shame.
这实在让我感到非常遗憾
You know, regrets can give you the motivation to strive for better.
从某个角度来看 遗憾也是迈向未来的希望
Remember this feeling and maybe you can make up for it in the future.
只要将其留存在心中 或许在未来就能得以实现
If fate wills it, that is.
在命运的指引下
Hopefully.
或许是吧…
KITASAN BLACK TO RETIRE FROM TWINKLE SERIES
(北部玄驹将从闪光系列赛引退)
Phew.
嘿咻
I pulled my back.
闪到腰了…
Are you okay?
你…你没事吧
Don't worry about me...
这只是小意思…
Are you a student from Tracen Academy?
你是特雷森学园的学生吗
Yes, I started in April.
是的 从四月开始
Are you trying to offload the boxes?
只要将这些货搬下来就行了对吧
Let me help you.
我来帮你
No need. I don't want to bother you.
咦 不用了 那怎么好意思
It's no bother at all.
请不用客气
I am confident in my strength.
我对力气活很有自信的
Watch me.
好 看我的
I can do this.
我搬…
You're my saviour.
哎呀 你帮了个大忙呢
Thank you, little girl.
谢谢你啊 小妹妹
My dad told me
我爸爸常跟我说
to help those in need
"见人有难就要马上相助"
and smile at those who are sad
"遇人失意就要一起欢笑"
so that everyone would smile always.
"如此大家就都能常保笑容"
Oh.
这样啊
I should go now.
那我就先走了
Wait.
啊 等一下
What's your name, little girl?
小妹妹 你叫什么名字
I'm Kitasan Black.
我叫北部玄驹
So she's quitting the Twinkle Series…
小北要从闪光系列赛引退了啊…
How long do you have to mope around for?
你要忧郁到什么时候
But...
可是…
Kita has two more races left.
小北还会在我们面前比赛两次耶
Are you going to watch her performance with a sulking face?
而你打算用这副 消沉的模样去看她吗
You're right.
说得也是…
What we can do for her is to cheer for her loudly and passionately.
我们所能做的就是像小北那样 充满活力地去为她加油了
That's right.
是啊 没错
Now, let's open the shop.
懂了的话 就快点准备开店吧
All right.
哦
Time to work.
好 开工吧
TAKE FRUITS AND VEGETABLES
(武蔬果店)
I pulled my back.
闪到腰了
Which lap is it?
现在是第几圈
The third lap.
第三圈
This was nothing to her in the past.
要是以前的小北 这根本就算不上什么的
Yeah...
的确…
She's trying so hard to delay her waning strength.
现在的她正在拼命地 去对抗逐渐衰退的自己
To do that, she can only engage in plain training like this.
为此 她只能做这种踏实的训练
She can do it.
那她没问题的
Slowly improving from ordinary training is her forté.
小北最厉害的 就是从踏实的训练中累积实力
Yeah.
是啊
You're working very hard, Crown.
你很有干劲呢 皇冠
Because I can't lose.
因为我不能输啊
I nearly caught up to her in Tenno Sho.
在上次的天皇赏里 还差一点就能追上她
But right when I decided to avenge myself in the next match,
但就在我决定 要在下次比赛报一箭之仇时…
she...
想不到…
Crown, you have faced Kitasan Black six times in the classics.
皇冠从经典级时起 已经跟北部玄驹交手了6次
We're in the same batch. We are rivals
我们既是同期 也是劲敌
and friends.
但又是朋友
When I heard that Kita is retiring...
听到这样的北部说她要引退
How should I put this?
这该怎么说呢
It's like your childhood playmate suddenly moves away.
有种向我说"再来一起玩吧"的孩子 突然间就搬家了的感觉
She has two races left.
但是还剩下两场比赛
Seeing her determination,
看到那不顾一切的身影
I want to work hard too.
就会有种我也得要加油的想法呢
Yeah.
是啊
Diamond, you won't sign up for the race?
光钻你不参加比赛吗
Huh?
咦
Arima Kinen, I mean.
参加有马纪念
This might be your last chance to race with Kitasan.
我想这是能跟北部一起奔跑 的最后机会了
If you're voted in by your fans...
如果能被粉丝投票选出的话…
But I don't think I can perform my best at the moment.
可是 现在的我 感觉不会有什么好表现
Is it because of Prix de l'Arc de Triomphe?
是因为凯旋门赏的影响吗
Yeah.
嗯
France has a different racecourse and a different track elevation.
在那边 无论是赛场 还是赛道的高低差
It's so different from Japan that it's like a whole new sport.
都跟日本完全不同 简直就像是不同的竞技类别
To win Prix de l'Arc de Triomphe,
要赢下凯旋门赏
I need to be ready
就必须要做好觉悟
to give up what I have learned and start from zero.
舍弃至今所积累起来的一切 从零开始修练
Even if I do that, I can't say for sure if I'll win.
而且即便如此 也不知道能不能够获胜
What is my goal?
什么是我必须去达成的事
What is the reason I run?
什么是我一路奔跑至今 该要凝视的目标
If I don't have an answer to them,
要是弄不清这些事情的话
I won't be able to progress.
我觉得我是无法向前迈进的
Taking your time to sort it out is not a bad idea either.
慢慢思考也不失为一个好主意啊
Hm?
咦
Some answers only appear when you pause and rest.
一定也有些事情 要停下来才能发现的
Thanks, Crown.
谢谢你 皇冠
Cheval, you're here.
骏逸在这里
Is something the matter?
有什么事吗
We're having dinner together.
我们正打算要去吃饭
Do you want to join us?
骏逸要不要一起去呢
No, thanks.
我就不用了
What's the matter, Cheval?
咦 你怎么了 骏逸
Do you have an upset tummy?
是肚子痛吗
No...
不是这样…
She's sulking because of Kitasan.
骏逸她现在啊 脑子里想的全都是北部的事
Why... Why would I?
怎…怎么会
Are you disappointed
是失落吗
or sad?
还是伤心呢
I'm not happy.
老实说 我很不开心
When I heard that Kitasan is retiring,
听到北部说她要引退
what I want to say is "Why?"
我心里只觉得"这是为什么"
I have never defeated her.
我一次也没有赢过那个家伙
How dare she quit now.
而她居然要先离开了
I understand what you're feeling.
我能理解这种心情
Huh?
咦
You're jealous of her. She makes you anxious.
一想到对方 就会心生嫉妒 焦虑不安
Yet somehow, you want to be her and you can't take your eyes off her.
但同时又被她所吸引 视线总是离不开她
You're envious and jealous of her.
对她的憧憬和嫉妒 这两种想法混杂在一起
It's like being in an unrequited love.
就像是苦恋着一个人的心情
In the end, I couldn't defeat her at all.
结果我一次也没赢过她
But you still have the chance.
但是 你还有机会
Two chances, in fact.
还有两次机会
Verxina...
姐姐…
That's right.
就是啊
During clutch moments,
骏逸在关键时刻时
you can be more focused than Verxina and me.
你的专注力 可是比我跟姐姐还要高呢
Two more chances, huh?
还有两次…的机会吗
UMA MUSUME PRETTY DERBY SEASON 3
《赛马娘 Pretty Derby 第三季》
Now that I think about it,
现在回想起来
I could barely handle her at the beginning.
起初她是我最难以应付的那种人
"WELCOME TO THE ACADEMY" She's cheerful and outgoing.
(恭喜入学) 很开朗 很活泼
-I'm... I'm Cheval Grand. -She gets along with everyone easily.
-我…我叫高尚骏逸 -很容易跟大家打成一片…
-My goal is to win G1. -She's the opposite of me.
-目标是赢得GI -跟我完全不一样
She's like Verxina or Vivlos.
- 请大家多多指教 - 我觉得她是像姐姐 或是强击那样的人
I'm Kitasan Black.
我是北部玄驹
My goal is to become a famous horse girl like Tokai Teio.
目标是成为像东海帝皇那样 既强大又闪亮的赛马娘
To do that, I need to win many races
首先要以连胜全胜的成绩
and win the classic triple crown.
赢下经典三冠
Nice to meet you.
请大家多多指教
She proclaims her ambition loudly and openly.
怀抱着远大的梦想 正大光明地表现出来
She's tough and has the stamina.
既强韧 又健壮 力气又大
She possesses everything I want.
她有着我想要的一切…
Truth be told,
老实说…
I envy her.
我真的很羡慕
I don't want to give up so I tried very hard.
不认输的我也试着去努力
Yet I could never be like her.
但我还是无法做到像她那样…
No matter how daunting the obstacles are,
不论她遇上多少道高墙
she'll work hard and overcome them.
她都会不断努力再努力 然后跨越过去
So I don't
所以我才会想
want to lose to her.
我不能输给她
I don't want to.
我不想输给那个家伙…
I want to defeat her.
我想要…赢过她
I want to defeat the strongest horse girl of our generation,
我想要赢过 号称当代最强的那个家伙
Kitasan Black.
赢过北部玄驹
So no matter how far behind I am,
不论我落后她多少
I won't give up.
我都绝对不会放弃
Because
因为我也一样
I'm just like her.
如同那个家伙一般
I will train, train, and train
不断努力再努力…
until I slowly catch up to her.
一点一点地接近她…
And next time...
下一次一定要…
I will overtake the shadow before me.
超越那个一直出现在我眼前的背影
The crisp opening music echoes through the autumn sky.
好的 嘹亮的开场乐 响彻了秋天的天空
An international G1 event, Japan Cup, is about to begin.
国际GI大赛 日本杯 马上就要开始了
Kitasan Black remains the most highly anticipated horse girl in the race.
最受瞩目的选手 果然还是北部玄驹吧
Yes, she announced her intention to quit Twinkle Series.
是啊 她宣布了 即将要从闪光系列赛中引退
Many fans gathered here to watch her performance again.
想必有不少粉丝 是特地来这里看她一眼的吧
All horse girls proceed to the gates confidently.
所有赛马娘带着气势十足的神情 陆续往闸门里就位
The popular Kitasan Black is ready in Gate 4.
人气王北部玄驹 则在4号闸门里准备就绪
All horse girls are here.
选手都到齐了
The last to enter the gate is No. 17, Big Subject.
最后进入闸门的 是17号伟大领域
The race starts now!
比赛现在开始
Everyone is vying for the lead.
首先是争夺领先地位
No. 4, Kitasan Black charges out.
4号北部玄驹冲了出来
Nice! She's off to a good start.
好啊 是好的开始
Yes, and she's focused.
看来她很专注呢
Go!
冲啊
Kitasan's silhouette is before me as usual.
今天北部的背影依然在我的眼前
Kitasan takes the lead as always.
像往常一样 由北部领先在众人之前
But today,
不过今天…
I won't let you get away with it.
我不会让你就这样逃掉的
Japan Cup is an international G1 race.
日本杯是国际GI大赛
Foreign horse girls are invited and it is often a tough match.
也会邀请海外赛马娘前来参赛 通常都会是高水平比赛
Why say this all of a sudden?
怎么突然说这个
The lap is 2,400-meter long, which is the real "classic'" length,
而且这个赛道是2400米草地 是"正统"经典距离
on par with other international turfs like Prix de l'Arc de Triomphe.
也就是与以凯旋门赏为首的 各国最高峰的草地赛事是相同距离
At times, a new record will be set, to everyone's surprise.
有时还会出现令人吃惊 打破赛事时间纪录的速度
To make sure that they don't fall behind, the stamina they train
为了不在艰困赛事中落后 所锻炼出来的体力
allows them to...
让她们能在激烈竞争中…
What?
怎么了
Kitasan Black only has two races left.
北部玄驹的比赛只剩下两场
I will devote all my attention to her performance.
所以必须好好看着才行
-Yeah. -Me too.
-是啊 -没错
The first 1,000-meter lap is completed in 60.02 seconds.
好的 最初的1000米 跑出的时间为60秒02
Leading the race is none other
领先在前 带领着这场比赛的选手果然还是她
than the Festival Girl, Kitasan Black.
祭典女孩 北部玄驹
You can do this, Kita.
加油啊 小北
Go!
加油啊
I failed to catch up to her in Tenno Sho,
在天皇赏时没能追上她
but this time, I'll overtake her.
但这次我一定要超越你
Go, Crown!
皇冠 加油啊
Kitasan Black is leading by 1.5 lengths.
领先在前的北部玄驹 距离后方一个半马身
Messy Eater takes the second spot. One Life takes the third.
第二名为狼吞虎咽 一生一世则是在第三名的位置
Cheval Grand is on the inside line and she's in fourth place.
内侧是高尚骏逸 现在爬到了第四名
Go, Cheval!
冲啊 骏逸
All the best!
加油啊 骏逸
Kitasan Black...
北部玄驹…
I hate you.
我讨厌你
We have the opposite personality.
你跟我的个性完全相反
Everyone loves you.
大家都喜欢你
You smile a lot. You're always energetic.
你的身边总是充斥着笑容和活力
I'm cold and aloof. Yet you barged into my world again and again.
就连面对这样的我 你也是一次又一次地闯进我的内心
They just passed the sign that says there are 600 meters left.
好的 通过了剩下600米的标识
Kitasan Black and the horse girls behind passed the fourth bend into the stretch.
北部玄驹带领着后方选手 通过第四弯道进入直线
Kitasan Black is still in the lead.
北部玄驹领先
She takes charge of the race.
北部玄驹一马当先
Oh!
居然
Here she is.
冲上来了 她冲上来了
Cheval Grand charges in from the back.
从后方冲出的是高尚骏逸
She set her eyes on Kitasan Black.
她紧咬着领先在前的北部玄驹
Kitasan Black.
北部玄驹
I hate you.
我讨厌你
You're always running in front of me,
你那总是跑在我眼前的背影
telling me how immature and pathetic I am.
不断提醒着 我有多不成熟 有多悲哀
You're an eyesore.
你好碍眼…
So annoying.
好可恨…
Yet
然而…
so dazzling.
却又是如此耀眼…
I don't know when it began.
不知从何时开始…
But I can't take my eyes off you.
我无法从你的身上移开我的目光…
It's Cheval Grand. She closes in.
是高尚骏逸 高尚骏逸追上来了
Kitasan Black.
北部玄驹
I hate you.
我讨厌你
You're the reason why
就是因为有你在
I'm here.
我才会走到这里…
To chase after your shadow,
因为有你的背影
I didn't give up and worked so hard until now.
我才能不轻言放弃地拼到今天…
Kitasan Black.
北部玄驹…
I...
我…
I truly
我其实…一直…
love you a lot.
很喜欢你啊
She's picking up her pace again?
居然还能再度加速
Cheval Grand is not slowing down.
高尚骏逸用那执着的脚程 紧追不舍
She's closing the gap between her and Kitasan Black.
渐渐地缩短 她和前方北部玄驹之间的差距
It's Cheval Grand!
是高尚骏逸
She has the lead now.
高尚骏逸领先
She overtook Kitasan Black and secures the first spot.
她超越北部玄驹 来到了领先位置
Atari also appears on the flank.
爱坛莉也从外侧不断逼进
Can Kitasan Black show us another burst of speed?
北部玄驹能爆发出最后的毅力吗
No, Cheval Grand is superior.
但是高尚骏逸棋高一着
She overtook Kitasan.
超过去了
Cheval Grand has the lead.
高尚骏逸领先
Cheval Grand!
是高尚骏逸
Cheval Grand crosses the finishing line
高尚骏逸以领先之姿
with her lead!
冲过终点
She defeated the other horse girls
打败众多名将
and won Japan Cup.
终于在这次的日本杯
This is her first G1 trophy!
夺下了她的第一个GI冠军
It's her seventh G1 race,
这是她第7次向GI挑战
and she finally won her first trophy!
终于亲手摘下了GI的胜利
She overtook Kitasan Black, who had the lead,
追上领先在前的北部玄驹
and outran Atari to victory.
甩开紧追不放的爱坛莉 漂亮夺冠
She showed us her amazing speed in this important tournament.
她在这场关键之战中 向我们展现了她那高超的实力
Well done, Cheval. Good job!
做得太好了 太厉害了 骏逸
Congratulations, Cheval.
恭喜你 骏逸
We three are now G1 champions!
这样我们三人就都是GI了
I...
我…
I did it.
我成功了…
Congratulations, Cheval.
恭喜你 骏逸
Mm.
嗯
Thank you, Kitasan.
谢谢你 北部
Kitasan...
北部…
I will surpass you and become a better horse girl.
我一定会成为 超越你的伟大赛马娘
Mm.
嗯
Well done! What a thrilling match!
辛苦了 是场很棒的比赛哦
I will be there for your next match too.
下一场比赛 我也一定会来竞马场的
Do your best in Arima Kinen!
有马纪念 要加油哦
It will be your last race.
再来是最后一场比赛了
We will be there to cheer for you!
我们会全力为你加油的
Arima Kinen.
有马纪念…
Is that so?
是吗…
The next race is...
下一场就是…
Kita.
小北
The live performance is over. What are you doing here?
LIVE都结束了 还在这里做什么呢
It'll be my last visit to Tokyo Racecourse in the Twinkle Series,
因为在闪光系列赛里 今天是最后一次在东京竞马场比赛
so I want to take a good look at it.
所以我想要来好好看看
I see.
这样啊…
My debut race was here too.
出道战也是在这里
I can still recall how nervous I was.
我现在都还记得 当时有多紧张
Derby too.
德比的时候也是…
Dura has such powerful techniques.
小鸣的跑法真的很厉害
Yeah.
嗯
From Tenno Sho to Japan Cup,
从秋季天皇赏到日本杯
I have raced many times here.
也参加过不少这里的GI赛事
Yeah.
嗯
Diamond.
光钻
Remember the time I told you I wondered what it was like to run in my final race?
你还记得我之前有跟你说过 "不知道跑引退赛是什么心情"吗
Huh?
咦
I have the answer now.
我现在明白了
It feels awful.
原来这感觉是如此令人难受
Kita...
小北…
The next race will be my final race.
下次的比赛 真的就是最后一场了啊…
Arima Kinen.
有马纪念…
I want to win it so badly.
好想赢哦…